# **LUCAS GANSBERG**

Father, husband, tinkerer, fullstack software engineer



(541)-591-8020

✓ lucas.gansberg@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/lucas-gansberg

# **SKILLS**

### **Technologies**

- React
- Vue
- NodeJS
- Terraform
- Docker
- GH Actions
- · Figma/Sketch
- AWS
  - SQS
  - SNS
  - DvnamoDB
  - Lambda
  - OpenSearch
  - CloudFront

### Languages & Markup

- Javascript/TypeScript
- Golang
- C# .NET
- C++
- HTML/CSS
- GraphQL

#### **Architecture**

- REST
- Microservices

# STRENGTHS

Self-Motivated Problem-Solving **Technical Management** 

# **EDUCATION**

B.S. Software Engineering Oregon Institute of Technology

# **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 12 years of industry experience. For the past three years I've managed a team of four highly skilled engineers, working on a variety of projects. I'm currently interested in leading another skilled group of engineers or working by their side.

### **EXPERIENCE**



### Software Engineering Manager

May 2021 - March 2024

- Managed a team of 4 developers responsible for 5 internal platforms, SDKs, libraries, and customer support.
- Lead the cross-functional engagement to re-architect our internal IdP provisioning platform.
- Collaborated daily with designers, developers, cross-functional teams, product, and program.
- · Developed engineering roadmaps and managed tasks to deliver features to our product catalog.



# **Senior Software Engineer III**

May 2019 - March 2021

- Built an internal AWS type console, to provide a one stop shop for technical products, and documentation.
- Delivered a Digital Asset Management platform UI
- Stood up an internal Data enrichment metric service
- IdP provisioning and documentation services.
- · Worked on multiple greenfield products.



### **Senior Software Engineer II**

March 2016 - May 2019

- Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) Scheduler leveraging gRPC for communication, accessed either by API or UI.
- Designed a UI to manage a server rack's physical resources based on the workloads requirements for compute, storage, and memory requirements.



## **Software Engineer**

July 2011 - March 2016

Software engineer focused on test automation, validating wireless standards/ protocols, wireless certification, and automation tools team.

- Worked on internal testing IDE and reporting tools.
- Wrapped native Intel wireless libraries using C# .NET for automated testing.
- Customer engagements to help leverage wireless features, along with OS integration: Microsoft, HP, Panasonic, and ActionTec.